<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-10-15T08:52:47-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">OldNewTimer.github.io</title><subtitle>My personal website.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Cause And Effect</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/24/cause-and-effect.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cause And Effect" /><published>2022-05-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/05/24/cause-and-effect</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/24/cause-and-effect.html">&lt;p&gt;I’m sitting in a room. I’m sitting in a room because I need to think.&lt;br /&gt;
It’s a thinking room. It’s a thinking room because it helps me think. It helps me think by being empty.&lt;br /&gt;
It’s empty because I hate distractions. I hate distractions because they stop me from thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I stop thinking, I get off task.&lt;br /&gt;
When I get off task, nothing gets done.&lt;br /&gt;
When nothing gets done, I am not done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(and so on)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I get up and I pace around the room. I pace around the room because it helps me think.&lt;br /&gt;
The circles I walk mirror those in my mind. The electrical impulses make their circuits through the neurons in my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The neurons need electricity because that’s the way it is.&lt;br /&gt;
I need to walk around because that’s the way it is.&lt;br /&gt;
Some things are just the way they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(and so on)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m talking to myself. I’m talking to myself because it helps me think.&lt;br /&gt;
When I talk to myself, I remember more.&lt;br /&gt;
When I remember more, I have better ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more ideas I have, the better chance the thinking can end.&lt;br /&gt;
The thinking can end when the problem is solved.&lt;br /&gt;
This time, the problem is that there is no problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am confused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(and so on?)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>OldNewTimer</name></author><summary type="html">I’m sitting in a room. I’m sitting in a room because I need to think. It’s a thinking room. It’s a thinking room because it helps me think. It helps me think by being empty. It’s empty because I hate distractions. I hate distractions because they stop me from thinking.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pitter Patter</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/07/pitter-patter.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pitter Patter" /><published>2022-05-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/05/07/pitter-patter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/07/pitter-patter.html">&lt;p&gt;I like the rain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking down path I go; sparkling shards of diamonds fall from above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I trudge on, and they begin to stick to my shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wind blows, casting another wave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am glitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I step inside, and realize that I am soaking wet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I like the rain.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>OldNewTimer</name></author><summary type="html">I like the rain.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Qwerty</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/04/19/qwerty.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Qwerty" /><published>2022-04-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-04-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/04/19/qwerty</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/04/19/qwerty.html">&lt;p&gt;Well, there was that one time that, in an email to his department head, he ensured her that if she needed any thong, he was the guy to get it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I” and “O” are, unfortunately, devious neighbors who enjoy playing pranks on those who pass by.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>OldNewTimer</name></author><summary type="html">Well, there was that one time that, in an email to his department head, he ensured her that if she needed any thong, he was the guy to get it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Valley</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/03/02/the-valley.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Valley" /><published>2022-03-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-03-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/03/02/the-valley</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/03/02/the-valley.html">&lt;p&gt;The valley, wedged in between two nearby peaks, was quiet. The orange ball had rolled across the sky, leaving now only streaks of yellow and crimson. Night would be upon the valley soon as the last remnants of heat followed their downward channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a ledge, overlooking the valley, sat a man. His name was Peter. Peter often hiked up to this spot; it was his favorite. He could see the sunset streaks above, sailing along the stretch of the fields and houses which dotted the landscape until hidden around a bend. The air up here was warm, infused with the sweet aroma of ripe grapes wafting from the nearby vineyard. Peter took a deep breath, inhaling it all, as to almost taste the wine the reds and whites would soon be made into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the square below, he could just make out the silhouettes of the townsfolk; figures that, like tiny matches, poked ways into their nests of tinder and kindling. One by one, the flame in each house would grow into a fire as brilliant light shone through all of the window panes. Laughter echoed through those ajar, spreading warmth all throughout the valley. Fathers and mothers sat down with their children for dinner. Their little Seans and Claras and Tommys and Janes had had a good day at school today, so that was a good enough reason for a night of spirit and celebration. The valley was quiet, but burning with passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most remote parts of the village were those areas where the ground began to slope at an awkward angle, making it undesirable to live upon. Loose rock would often roll and rebound off of the exposed faces, crashing into the cushion of vegetation below. The townsfolk knew this; for nature told them. It whispered in earthly vibrations, and sang through the birds, scattering in tune to the rhythm of the boulders. And then, when winter came, tides of snow would erode the rock face, supplying the mountains with more ammunition to lob down in the next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, despite all of this danger, there was a structure nestled in the thick of it. An ancient foundation perched on a lone outcrop, one which had been in service to a long-gone guardstower. And like its predecessor, the hut that now hunched upon it was strong. It was fashioned of sturdy brick masonry and a shield that was its metal roof; it had been built to survive a beating. Every day, the mountains would wage battle with the hut, which would only stare back in quiet defiance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the ledge, Peter sat, and sighed. Humming from an endless repertoire of somber melodies, he tapped a relaxed beat on the tall grass beside him. After each had concluded, he would close his eyes. Peter felt as the greenery around him rustled in the sighs of wind. He could hear the distant hoots of owls, the chirps of crickets, the cracks and snaps of other creatures wandering through the underbrush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything was good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His tune stopped abruptly though; he heard the whispers, the flutters, the caws. Nature was warning him. His eyes shot open in sharp observance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was slow at first. Dust and stones sprinkled down, tapping the same beat of Peter’s song on the roof of his house. It was as if the mountain had heard the tune and wanted to echo it back. But the pace quickened with the rhythm; larger, jagged rocks pierced the corrugated metal. Sticks and twigs rapped like drumsticks along with the band. Large clumps of earth splattered, in course creating sharp thumps that echoed throughout the structure. It was a crescendo of destructive melody, rising in volume and complexity. Thunderous clashes of dense granite blocks phased through the roof, striking the very foundation of the building. The bones of the warriors rattled in their graves below, for even their resting place had been disturbed. One final, almost imperceptibly quiet note was played through the last root of a dangling tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Snap!”. Peter closed his eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it all came crashing down. The dust and stones, the rocks and blocks, the sticks and twigs, the clumps – and finally trunk. With gravity as its tempo, the earth enveloped Peter’s house in an explosive recapitulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Opening his eyes once more, he now did not resume in song. The sun had set now, and the glittering stars had replaced it. They almost seemed to be watching and mimicking the lights of the valley; they reflected the wonder, the love, the happiness. And in the distance, Peter could see that the lights now shone for him. He may not have had his house, but he still had a home.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>OldNewTimer</name></author><summary type="html">The valley, wedged in between two nearby peaks, was quiet. The orange ball had rolled across the sky, leaving now only streaks of yellow and crimson. Night would be upon the valley soon as the last remnants of heat followed their downward channel.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Filet Mignon Of The Sky</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/12/14/filet-mignon-of-the-sky.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Filet Mignon Of The Sky" /><published>2021-12-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/12/14/filet-mignon-of-the-sky</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/12/14/filet-mignon-of-the-sky.html">&lt;p&gt;They’re so peaceful now - the birds. Flapping from tree to tree, without a care in the world. They sing songs, collect tidbits for their nests, and love it all. At night, they are afraid, but together they stay and together they will be in the morning. On one of these mornings, a dove lands near me, eyeing a puddle; it’s the last sigh of yesterday’s sickly storm. The dove glances in my direction as one of its eyes meets mine. It cocks its head to the left, and then to the right. It is clearly amused by this huge figure that is staring at it. Maybe the birds write about watching people too. I don’t know, their wings may be poetry that we can never understand the simplistic beauty of. Anyways, I lift my pen from the paper I’m rambling on and begin to draw on another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not that good of an artist. Never had any formal classes; a doodle is about my level of experience. I start to draw the outline, then little lines here and there that show depth and form. Genius! But I don’t know where exactly the lines are supposed to go, so, I guess. Brilliant!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t the stage for color yet, that’s a whole different ballpark. Besides, all I have is this fountain pen. Fair. I begin to add the finer details; I poke on some eyes (no more than two, please), a little beak here and there, maybe some feathers (that’s necessary, stupid). Then I start to shade the bird. Starting with a slanted pen, I graze it back and forth on the paper, making faint and jagged lines along features I want highlighted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Happy little trees,” I think to myself. I’ve started with some quality details, but too many to a point where my wrist has other plans. I finish it out with some more happy little tree strokes, albeit they may have gone through a bit of a drought. It’ll buff out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last thing, of course: my signature. I scribble it in the bottom right, along with the date. It’ll be useful when it’s hanging in the Louvre. And with that, I put down my pen to see its offspring. Ah, yes, the rubber ducky franken-chicken. Brilliant. What a masterpiece. Maybe I should stick to writing words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dove is beautiful though. That’s what really matters.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>OldNewTimer</name></author><summary type="html">They’re so peaceful now - the birds. Flapping from tree to tree, without a care in the world. They sing songs, collect tidbits for their nests, and love it all. At night, they are afraid, but together they stay and together they will be in the morning. On one of these mornings, a dove lands near me, eyeing a puddle; it’s the last sigh of yesterday’s sickly storm. The dove glances in my direction as one of its eyes meets mine. It cocks its head to the left, and then to the right. It is clearly amused by this huge figure that is staring at it. Maybe the birds write about watching people too. I don’t know, their wings may be poetry that we can never understand the simplistic beauty of. Anyways, I lift my pen from the paper I’m rambling on and begin to draw on another.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Infantas</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/12/13/infantas.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Infantas" /><published>2021-12-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/12/13/infantas</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/12/13/infantas.html">&lt;p&gt;There was a world&lt;br /&gt;
not far from here&lt;br /&gt;
behind a Venus moon,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where people all&lt;br /&gt;
with life, in awe&lt;br /&gt;
played a different tune.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This world lost&lt;br /&gt;
called Infantas&lt;br /&gt;
was developed to the T.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peace did blare&lt;br /&gt;
rang in the air&lt;br /&gt;
throughout society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now this old place&lt;br /&gt;
unlike our space&lt;br /&gt;
time could not be wrought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a ship to wave&lt;br /&gt;
and captain slain&lt;br /&gt;
back to port it brought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Old men gave&lt;br /&gt;
to child’s play&lt;br /&gt;
and crawled into the womb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loved and dear&lt;br /&gt;
from every year&lt;br /&gt;
emerged from greying tomb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soldiers rose&lt;br /&gt;
with ironed clothes&lt;br /&gt;
to greet their families.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gifts were back&lt;br /&gt;
and then rewrapped&lt;br /&gt;
under Christmas trees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of ash&lt;br /&gt;
nations clashed&lt;br /&gt;
and back to dust they went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A farmer’s child&lt;br /&gt;
in weather mild&lt;br /&gt;
came back from years’ lament.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More trees grew&lt;br /&gt;
with greener hue&lt;br /&gt;
as span of people dwindled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sticks and twigs&lt;br /&gt;
made lovely jigs&lt;br /&gt;
as gatherers found their kindle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon the land&lt;br /&gt;
no grain, just sand&lt;br /&gt;
lost all its humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this place lost&lt;br /&gt;
called Infantas&lt;br /&gt;
faded without memory.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>OldNewTimer</name></author><summary type="html">There was a world not far from here behind a Venus moon,</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Submarine</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/12/05/submarine.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Submarine" /><published>2021-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/12/05/submarine</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/12/05/submarine.html">&lt;p&gt;And there was that one time, a cold, somber winter, that I lay in bed. There’s a little routine I have - when I become a submarine. That night, it went something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Seal the hatch and prepare for submersion!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes, sir, right away sir, with haste and pride, sir. Sir, we’re on our way, sir”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s enough private, all for now”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The submarine sprawls quietly on the ocean floor, a bed of seaweed to buffer from the coils of coral. In his quarters the captain is awakened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sir, our pressure levels are unsustainable at this depth”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Then bring us up private!”, says groggy eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Private Wires is a bit like a penny. He’s as tranquil and honest as Abe sometimes, but he can immediately flip and become frightened and excessively meticulous, caged up in a prison of marble pillars. Either way, he doesn’t think his words come across as helpful unless he utters a whole earful of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reach shallower waters and all is well, but not a useful one at that. I can almost hear the fan of seagulls gently toss the vessels of the vessel; drifting yet again from ebb to flow and head to toe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sir, Sir!” Wires needs to add his two cents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What is it, private?”, says red eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re at too shallow a depth, they may spot us!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“God dammit Wires! Send us down again but don’t burn us up this time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yessir.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The submarine, like a sea turtle, drifts on the currents as the crew slumbers in their shell of steel and algae. All is well again; we are prepared for the coming storm.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>OldNewTimer</name></author><summary type="html">And there was that one time, a cold, somber winter, that I lay in bed. There’s a little routine I have - when I become a submarine. That night, it went something like this:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Four Men Stand</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/05/25/four-men-stand.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Four Men Stand" /><published>2021-05-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-05-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/05/25/four-men-stand</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/05/25/four-men-stand.html">&lt;p&gt;Four men stand in the forest. Surrounded in darkness, they watch the ground. Smoke is rising everywhere; a fallen torch has set a stump afire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Go fill up the water jugs and bring them here,” one man says. His tone reflects that he is indeed the leader. I listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Into the darkness I tread down the winding path, picking up the jugs as I go along. I go alone; the others stay behind. The midnight air is all around me, but tinged with smoke it drives one not to rest. I keep going. There is a clearing with the spigot. I fill up one with water and set it down, then the next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now here is the hard part; I pick them up and begin to walk. It is a slow walk. I stumble for a minute or two, set the jugs down for a few seconds, and then start back up. I can see a faint glow, and my pace quickens. Stop, go, stop go. Tall grass wraps around my ankles while invisible insects cling to me. My heart is pounding, my arms ache, but I know that I must keep going. Without this water, the fire will spread until it consumes all of our land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last push is all it takes, a stumbling halt and I drop the jugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hold my light,” the leader orders. I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The others take the jugs and begin to pour. It rains on the warm soil, washing away the smoke. The ground is getting colder, but there is still warmth below. The leader begins to dig a moat with his hands, feeling for any embers that may remain. Each faint glow is extinguished with a splash from the jug. Little by little, the glow of the fire is replaced by that of our own faces. We have done it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four men stand in the forest. Surrounded in darkness, they watch the ground. Steam is rising everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lift the torch, my soul afire.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>OldNewTimer</name></author><summary type="html">Four men stand in the forest. Surrounded in darkness, they watch the ground. Smoke is rising everywhere; a fallen torch has set a stump afire.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Choose</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/02/choose.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Choose" /><published>2020-10-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-10-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/02/choose</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/02/choose.html">&lt;p&gt;“Choose” echoes throughout the hall as it has many times before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly enough, this hall is not your regular out-of-the-box-with-standard-features sort of hall. You see, the hall, in fact, is not much of a hall at all. The passage is laid more like the canal through one’s own ear; oblong, with abstract curves, a slippery yet dry film plasters on the walls and floor, and other assorted details for which I care not to mention. The importance of this manifestation is not that this non-hall of a nonexistent place is shaped like in this manner, but rather of the message reverberating throughout it, for I am not the one uttering it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Choose” again continues, railing into my own ear like a freight train of fear and fascination. I brace myself on the wall until the movement stops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since I had stumbled into this place I couldn’t seem to find where I had entered. What was this choice the voice kept mentioning? What was my purpose here? What, in fact, was here. I had been through a lot in these past couple… days. Wait, no, that’s not right… Weeks? Wrong again. Months… that’s it! Months of toil and uncertainty. Was it my fault? Yes, I will admit. I’m still figuring out who I am, but there is some figuring that is out of the hands of even the cleverest mathematician; so busy in the theory behind it all that the simplest of arithmetic is foreign. I had been so caught up in the future that I forgot how to tend to the present. And so the time faded as a flame with no feeder. Until now, which gifted a moment of clarity through which to reflect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The voice again makes its way through the hall, and now I feel its message even stronger than before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The choice. Last chance. End of the line. No going back. A future uncertain because of a past neglected. What should I do now? There’s nothing to go back to. Everything has moved on, yet I’m still here. All these thoughts darting around with nowhere to go except to rebound in the hall. The walls are shaking; chips of paint fluttering to the floor, dust lifted from the floor to once again fly. Fissures flash, the hall fades, and I find myself staring at a face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sir, you’re holding up the line. Do you want a ticket or not?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How far does the line go?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Seattle.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ll take that then.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“One-way ‘r round-trip?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“One-way, please.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hall is empty now. Only footprints in the again-settled dust remain. Echoes of a choice made, and a past enduring.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>OldNewTimer</name></author><summary type="html">“Choose” echoes throughout the hall as it has many times before.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mirage</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/12/mirage.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mirage" /><published>2020-07-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/12/mirage</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/12/mirage.html">&lt;p&gt;As ash to ash and dust to dust,&lt;br /&gt;
Traversing through a stolid land&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Approaching us, it billows;&lt;br /&gt;
Neglecting to stoop, instead to rise&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My vision is clouded by the static it brings.&lt;br /&gt;
I cannot see you. You cannot see me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our connection remains, but the chain;&lt;br /&gt;
It rusts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The foundry from which it was forged is cold and bare.&lt;br /&gt;
The bond weakens from wear and neglect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I grab the chain - pulling tight;&lt;br /&gt;
Clinging to the last fiber - the final chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snap!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The link has departed - from one to two&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whirlwind winds with dust and ash&lt;br /&gt;
Spinning thoughts in a tumult of gray&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It throws me out, thrashing and swinging&lt;br /&gt;
Spitting a smirk as it leaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facing a long and desolate path&lt;br /&gt;
No end, yet I must keep moving&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking&lt;br /&gt;
Trudging&lt;br /&gt;
Pacing&lt;br /&gt;
Grudging&lt;br /&gt;
Racing&lt;br /&gt;
Sprinting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huffing&lt;br /&gt;
Slowing&lt;br /&gt;
Puffing&lt;br /&gt;
Stopping&lt;br /&gt;
And dropping to my knees&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I see in the distance, a gleam&lt;br /&gt;
A blip on the horizon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standing there, bringing newfound hope&lt;br /&gt;
I make for the crest of the hill&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And find nothing but another desolate path&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To another blip on the horizon&lt;br /&gt;
To mountains, rivers&lt;br /&gt;
To days of gales and droughts&lt;br /&gt;
To more hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through all the noise, pain, worry, and sorrow&lt;br /&gt;
Finding the real path &lt;br /&gt;
To you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>OldNewTimer</name></author><summary type="html">As ash to ash and dust to dust, Traversing through a stolid land</summary></entry></feed>